<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gabo Esquivel - Software Engineer</title>
    <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gabo Esquivel - Software Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gaboesquivel.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TypeScript Code Generation from GraphQL</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2020/typescript-code-generation-from-graphql/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2020/typescript-code-generation-from-graphql/</guid>
      <description>Presentation at GraphQL Texas, an event sponsored and organized by BoltSource.io
    Presentación Comunidades de software + TypeScript y Graphql en español para Community Conf, PanamaJS.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TicoBlockchain 2019 Recap</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2019/ticoblockchain-2019-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2019/ticoblockchain-2019-recap/</guid>
      <description>On saturday February 2nd 2019 the first international crypto and blockchain conference in Costa Rica was held at Club Unión in San José. The famous club founded in 1925 was the preferred meeting place of the upper political and business classes during the liberal period; and now it&amp;rsquo;s becoming an important center for multiple activities related to cryptocurrencies and blockchain innovation in Costa Rica.
The event was co-organized by blockchain organizations and groups based in Costa Rica: BlockchainCR, AsoBlockchain, EOS Costa Rica, Comunidad Bitcoin and Nimiq; And counted with support and sporship from local and international companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Crypto Conference in Costa Rica</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2019/international-crypto-conference-in-costa-rica/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2019/international-crypto-conference-in-costa-rica/</guid>
      <description>On February 2nd 2019, the first international blockchain and cryptocurrency conference in Costa Rica will be held in San José.
You’ll listen to great business and technical conferences, as well as actual technical workshops for running smart contracts and understanding what blockchains are.
Ticoblockchain participants will have the choice of attending speeches on two separate tracks occurring simultaneously. A business oriented track meant for those looking to obtain a well rounded picture of the current state of blockchain and cryptocurrencies, both globally and in Costa Rica.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommendations to Enhance your Github Flow</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2018/recommendations-to-enhance-your-github-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2018/recommendations-to-enhance-your-github-flow/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on software development for 10 years now and along the way, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to collaborate on several open source projects and also worked on many non-open source projects where we used Github as our version control repository, on small and large teams.
On my journey, I&amp;rsquo;ve followed different workflows depending on the project and today I want to share with you what I consider to be a effective and pragmatic workflow for building and maintaining good quality software that can be applied to any project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain Technology in Costa Rica</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2018/blockchain-technology-in-costa-rica/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2018/blockchain-technology-in-costa-rica/</guid>
      <description>On September 2017 BlockchainCR was founded, a community hub for studying and promoting blockchain technology in Costa Rica. It is an organization founded with the intention of making Costa Rica a leading country in the use of blockchain, decentralized networks, and distributed ledger technologies.
 We meet regularly to network with people interested in blockchain technology, including innovators, entrepreneurs, engineers, entrepreneurs, educators, government and anyone curious about blockchain and its many applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get in Touch</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 12:07:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tweets</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/tweets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 12:07:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/tweets/</guid>
      <description>Tweets by gaboesquivel</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Node.js Version Switching</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2015/automatic-node.js-version-switching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2015/automatic-node.js-version-switching/</guid>
      <description>When working on multiple Node.js projects it is important to configure your development environment to automatically switch to right node version for a particular project. You can automate this task on many different ways. I opted for using using a module called avn that works both with nvm and n for automatic Node.js version switching. In my case I use nvm as my version manager. In order to achieve automatic version switching with avn you need to add a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Continuous Delivery</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2015/on-continuous-delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2015/on-continuous-delivery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Continuous delivery is practice in software development in which development teams work in a way that allows companies to update their systems at any point in time or continuously through automated processes, the system’s code base is always deployable and tested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-it-important&#34;&gt;Why is it important?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuous delivery is a more efficient way to build software as it enables a team to get constant feedback on the application’s changes and updates, allowing you detect problems early and consequently improve quality, reduce costs and deployment frictions. This constant feedback also gives the team a realistic view of development progress instead of relying on perceptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuous Delivery gives a company the ability to react quickly and respond to change. Having fluid a process of software development allows you to make changes on your strategy more easily and rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices for Designing RESTful APIs</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2015/best-practices-for-designing-restful-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2015/best-practices-for-designing-restful-apis/</guid>
      <description>An application-programming interface (API) exposes functionality of a software application for other software clients to use. Through APIs applications interact with each other and share data without any user knowledge or intervention.
Modern web applications typically have RESTful JSON APIs. REST stands for Representational State Transfer and it is a software architecture style consisting of guidelines and best practices for building scalable web services. JSON stands for JavaScript Object Notation and it is a minimal, readable format for structuring data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Films and Documentaries Worth Watching</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2015/films-and-documentaries-worth-watching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2015/films-and-documentaries-worth-watching/</guid>
      <description>This is a curated list of films and documentaries related to the internet, programming and hacking. If you are a web developer or consider yourself a problem solver you will probably enjoy them. These films contain historical and philosophical content on subjects related to programming, the internet, the evolution of human consciousness, activism, social action, environmental causes, open source and free software movements.
The Internet&amp;rsquo;s Own Boy: The Story of Aaron Swartz (2014) The Internet’s Own Boy follows the story of programming prodigy and information activist Aaron Swartz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In-Place Editing with contenteditable and AngularJS</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2014/in-place-editing-with-contenteditable-and-angularjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2014/in-place-editing-with-contenteditable-and-angularjs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In-place editing provides an easy way to let the user edit parts of a page without having to be redirected to an edit page. Instead, the user can just click around on a page an edit the elements he or she wishes to change – without reloading the page. When the user hovers over an editable area, the background color of the element changes. When clicked, the text becomes editable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can make an element editable by adding the contenteditable attribute in your markup. This attribute has three possible values: &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;inherit&lt;/code&gt;. Specifying inherit will make the element editable if it’s immediate parent is editable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;editable&amp;quot; contenteditable=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following directive uses contenteditable attribute and ng-model for data binding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-height=&#34;452&#34; data-theme-id=&#34;8070&#34; data-slug-hash=&#34;mgCAG&#34; data-default-tab=&#34;result&#34; class=&#39;codepen&#39;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&#39;http://codepen.io/gaboesquivel/pen/mgCAG/&#39;&gt;Editing Page Elements with contenteditable&lt;/a&gt; by Gabo Esquivel (&lt;a href=&#39;http://codepen.io/gaboesquivel&#39;&gt;@gaboesquivel&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&#39;http://codepen.io&#39;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node.js HTTPS and SSL Certificate for Development</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2014/node.js-https-and-ssl-certificate-for-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2014/node.js-https-and-ssl-certificate-for-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HTTPS is the HTTP protocol over TLS/SSL and HTTPS is required to protect your data. It is the most popular network protocol for establishiing secure connections for exchanging documents on the internet. It is basically HTTP carried over a TCP socket, which has been secured using SSL. Transport Layer Security (TLS) and Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) are cryptographic protocols designed to provide communication security. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll show how to create a self-signed SSL certificate and set up an express 4.0 project that uses it for local development purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;self-signed-ssl-certificate&#34;&gt;Self-Signed SSL Certificate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two kinds of certificates: those signed by a &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Certificate_authority&#34;&gt;Certificate Authority&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;, or CA, and &amp;lsquo;self-signed certificates&amp;rsquo;. A Certificate Authority is a trusted source for an SSL certificate, and using a certificate from a CA allows your users to be trust the identity of your website. In most cases, you would want to use a CA-signed certificate in a production environment - for testing purposes, however, a self-signed certicate will do just fine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Gulp.js</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2014/introduction-to-gulp.js/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2014/introduction-to-gulp.js/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Automation of repetitive and critical tasks is key to develop a successful software product. Automated tasks will minimize software cost, reduce software delivery time as well as improving the product quality and reduce human error. Investing time in automating tasks will allow you to focus on developing features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“War is of vital importance to the state; hence it is a subject of inquiry which can on no account be neglected”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sun Tzu, Art of War&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post I will introduce you to Gulp.js, a javascript task runner that helps you automate your development process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;##Setting Up your Web App Build System&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When developing modern web applications there are critical tasks you want to automate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;testing: code linting, unit testing, e2e tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;css preprocessing ( sass, less, …)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;optimization: concatenating and minifying css and scripts, compressing new or modified images, &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deploying updates to a staging or production server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many tools that will help you automate these tasks. Which one to choose? Grunt, Gulp, Brunch, Broccoli,…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2012 Grunt.js came out and it was quickly adopted by the community, plugins started to proliferate and it became king for task automation on the client side, playing well with Bower and Yeoman. Like many other developers I’ve been using Grunt on my projects and it gets the job done but recently I started to use Gulp, another open source project with faster build times and a Unix/Node philosophical approach to solve problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gulp.js focuses on code over configuration. By harnessing the power of Node streams, it enables faster build times by avoiding the need to write temporary files to disk. This is one of the main differences with Grunt. Stream instances are basically Unix pipes. They can be readable, writable or both and are easy to reason about &amp;ndash; you can pipe a readable stream to a writable stream by doing readableStream.pipe(writableStream).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Streams come to us from the earliest days of unix and have proven themselves over the decades as a dependable way to compose large systems out of small components that do one thing well.&lt;br&gt;
You can then plug the output of one stream to the input of another and use libraries that operate abstractly on streams to institute higher-level flow control.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;substack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview of Angular Generators – April 2014</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2014/overview-of-angular-generators-april-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2014/overview-of-angular-generators-april-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a short and opinionated review of the AngularJS generators on npm as of April 19th, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of generators on npm and it&amp;rsquo;s a little hard to decide which one to use or fork, since we don&amp;rsquo;t want to reinvent the wheel. Currently the only way to compare them is to try them one by one and that&amp;rsquo;s a very time consuming task. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll try to give you an overview of some generators I&amp;rsquo;ve explored recently hoping it will save you some time. I’ll follow &lt;a href=&#34;http://cliffmeyers.com/blog/2013/4/21/code-organization-angularjs-javascript&#34;&gt;Cliff Meyer&amp;rsquo;s Code Organization Categorization&lt;/a&gt; to describe their code structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most generators still use the &amp;ldquo;Sock Drawer&amp;rdquo; directory organization, an approach that I personally avoid, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t scale well but it works for small projects. I prefer a modular structure as suggested on latest &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1XXMvReO8-Awi1EZXAXS4PzDzdNvV6pGcuaF4Q9821Es/pub&#34;&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s Best Practice Recommendations for Angular App Structure&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the benefits of modularization are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Encapsulation:&lt;/strong&gt; Code, styles and tests related to specific feature will be contained on the same directory.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Context:&lt;/strong&gt;  Code lives in given context by feature. This is specially important to developers new to the application, who will find it easier to connect the dots.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Code Reusabilty:&lt;/strong&gt; You would be able to reuse modules across projects and clients, Eg mobile and web-client could share autentication modules or resources ( models ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of Angular generators and their characteristics (some of them are fullstack generators):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Software in Paradise, aka Costa Rica</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2014/developing-software-in-paradise-aka-costa-rica/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2014/developing-software-in-paradise-aka-costa-rica/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coming back to Costa Rica and enjoy my country while working on software applications is one of the best decisions I ever made. Check out these pictures I took with my phone at Playa Manzanillo, near to Santa Teresa - Mal País, a natural paradise with world class surfing that ranks among the most beautiful beaches of Costa Rica and you&amp;rsquo;ll agree is the best place to live or invest in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;center-align-wrapper&#34; style=&#34;margin: 3px 0;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&#34;playa-manazanillo-sunset&#34; src=&#34;https://gaboesquivel.com/img/2014/01/playa-manazanillo-sunset-300x225.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&#34;vacas-playa-manzanillo&#34; src=&#34;https://gaboesquivel.com/img/2014/01/vacas-playa-manzanillo-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;center-align-wrapper&#34; style=&#34;margin: 3px 0;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&#34;playa-manzanillo-reef&#34; src=&#34;https://gaboesquivel.com/img/2014/01/playa-manzanillo-reef-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&#34;rocks-playa-manzanillo&#34; src=&#34;https://gaboesquivel.com/img/2014/01/rocks-playa-manzanillo-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Santa Teresa was recently awarded by Trip Advisor as the #1 highest-rated travel location in all of both Central and South America. Malpais and Montezuma both have many of the best restaurants in the entire country, since many international chefs have moved to the area. The area is also a major center of Costa Rica Yoga with over a dozen places to learn/practice and many yoga retreats and surf+yoga retreat combinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Elion Chin, co-founder of MoodLogic - one of the first online music recommendation systems, is leading &lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; src=&#34;http://bit.ly/SiliconBeachCR&#34;&gt;Silicon Beach&lt;/a&gt; a forum for entrepreneurs &amp; people looking to invest in, work at, advise or network with startups in Costa Rica to promote the technology talent of Costa Rica and drive the start-up culture in a fulfilling and healthy environment to deliver the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;center-align-wrapper&#34;&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&#34;Silicon Beach Costa Rica&#34; src=&#34;https://gaboesquivel.com/img/2014/01/silicon-beach-costa-rica.png&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing the Data Store for Your Web App</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2013/choosing-the-data-store-for-your-web-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2013/choosing-the-data-store-for-your-web-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When choosing a database for your application, you need ask yourself many questions and there are important rules about Data Architecture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there’s no standard solution that fits all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the business and it’s data defines the architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you need to find the right tool that does job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you can use multiple databases, different types depending on the characteristics of each data subset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is very important to decide carefully, after your application grown it could be very difficult to change. The CAP theorem, also known as Brewer’s theorem, states that it is impossible for a distributed computer system to simultaneously provide all three of the following guarantees:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consistency (all nodes see the same data at the same time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Availability (a guarantee that every request receives a response about whether it was successful or failed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partition tolerance (the system continues to operate despite arbitrary message loss or failure of part of the system)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;center-align-wrapper&#34;&gt;
&lt;img  alt=&#34;CAP Theorem - Venn Diagram&#34; src=&#34;https://gaboesquivel.com/img/2013/09/cap_venn.png&#34; width=&#34;547&#34; height=&#34;520&#34; /&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;
Once you have defined which of those guarantees is less important for your app and can be sacrificed, you have a smaller subset of options to choose from. However this not the only thing you need to consider, you may want to use a specific framework such as Hibernate, Spring, Django or WordPress, and take advantage of the of-the-shelf capabilities, in that case you want to use a SQL database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization in Costa Rica</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2013/data-visualization-in-costa-rica/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2013/data-visualization-in-costa-rica/</guid>
      <description>I’m very excited to announce that we’re starting a data visualization meetup group in Costa Rica!
At Hack/Hackers San José event I finally had the pleasure to meet Yuri Engelhardt in person after months of exchanging emails and ideas about data visualization. Yuri is the co-founder of Show Me Data, an annual multidisciplinary course and public event that brings together the University of Amsterdam (UvA) and the Utrecht Graduate School of Visual Art and Design (maHKU) students to get familiar with the world of data visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Engineering Podcasts</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2012/my-favorite-engineering-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2012/my-favorite-engineering-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;updated on 05/2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;javascript-jabber&#34;&gt;Javascript Jabber&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply the best Javascript podcast out there.
By Charles Max Wood, Joe Eames, Merrick Christensen, AJ O&amp;rsquo;Neal, Jamison Dance, Aaron Frost&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://javascriptjabber.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://javascriptjabber.com/&#34;&gt;http://javascriptjabber.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nodeup-8211-nodejs-awesomeness&#34;&gt;NodeUp – NodeJS Awesomeness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A node.js podcast put together by @ffloat and @dshaw..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nodeup.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;nodeup.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-changelog-8211-open-source-moves-fast-keep-up&#34;&gt;The ChangeLog – Open Source Moves Fast. Keep up.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Changelog is a weekly podcast and blog that covers what’s fresh and new in Open Source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://thechangelog.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;thechangelog.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Only Live Once</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/bio/</guid>
      <description>My name is Gabriel Esquivel, a sofware engineer from Costa Rica, everyone calls me Gabo. I’m a proponent of decentralized applications, open-source technology stacks, devops culture, lightweight agilism and modern web technologies.
I help companies develop software products and make technical decisions, working with stakeholders and developers in the design and implementation of software applications, taking ideas from conception to production and successful execution.
I have several years of experience working with startups, agencies and established companies developing web and mobile applications with a focus on FinTech and Blockchain in the recent years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
