<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blockchain on Gabo Esquivel - Software Engineer</title>
    <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/categories/blockchain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blockchain on Gabo Esquivel - Software Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gaboesquivel.com/categories/blockchain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TicoBlockchain 2019 Recap</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2019/ticoblockchain-2019-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2019/ticoblockchain-2019-recap/</guid>
      <description>On saturday February 2nd 2019 the first international crypto and blockchain conference in Costa Rica was held at Club Unión in San José. The famous club founded in 1925 was the preferred meeting place of the upper political and business classes during the liberal period; and now it&amp;rsquo;s becoming an important center for multiple activities related to cryptocurrencies and blockchain innovation in Costa Rica.
The event was co-organized by blockchain organizations and groups based in Costa Rica: BlockchainCR, AsoBlockchain, EOS Costa Rica, Comunidad Bitcoin and Nimiq; And counted with support and sporship from local and international companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Crypto Conference in Costa Rica</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2019/international-crypto-conference-in-costa-rica/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2019/international-crypto-conference-in-costa-rica/</guid>
      <description>On February 2nd 2019, the first international blockchain and cryptocurrency conference in Costa Rica will be held in San José.
You’ll listen to great business and technical conferences, as well as actual technical workshops for running smart contracts and understanding what blockchains are.
Ticoblockchain participants will have the choice of attending speeches on two separate tracks occurring simultaneously. A business oriented track meant for those looking to obtain a well rounded picture of the current state of blockchain and cryptocurrencies, both globally and in Costa Rica.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain Technology in Costa Rica</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2018/blockchain-technology-in-costa-rica/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2018/blockchain-technology-in-costa-rica/</guid>
      <description>On September 2017 BlockchainCR was founded, a community hub for studying and promoting blockchain technology in Costa Rica. It is an organization founded with the intention of making Costa Rica a leading country in the use of blockchain, decentralized networks, and distributed ledger technologies.
 We meet regularly to network with people interested in blockchain technology, including innovators, entrepreneurs, engineers, entrepreneurs, educators, government and anyone curious about blockchain and its many applications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
