<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>open source on Gabo Esquivel - Software Developer</title>
    <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/categories/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in open source on Gabo Esquivel - Software Developer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gaboesquivel.com/categories/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recommendations to Enhance your Github Flow</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2018/recommendations-to-enhance-your-github-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2018/recommendations-to-enhance-your-github-flow/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on software development for 10 years now and along the way, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to collaborate on several open source projects and also worked on many non-open source projects where we used Github as our version control repository, on small and large teams.
On my journey, I&amp;rsquo;ve followed different workflows depending on the project and today I want to share with you what I consider to be a effective and pragmatic workflow for building and maintaining good quality software that can be applied to any project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain Technology in Costa Rica</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2018/blockchain-technology-in-costa-rica/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2018/blockchain-technology-in-costa-rica/</guid>
      <description>On September 2017 BlockchainCR was founded, a community hub for studying and promoting blockchain technology in Costa Rica. It is an organization founded with the intention of making Costa Rica a leading country in the use of blockchain, decentralized networks, and distributed ledger technologies.
 We meet regularly to network with people interested in blockchain technology, including innovators, entrepreneurs, engineers, entrepreneurs, educators, government and anyone curious about blockchain and its many applications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
