<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>database on Gabo Esquivel - Software Engineer</title>
    <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/categories/database/</link>
    <description>Recent content in database on Gabo Esquivel - Software Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gaboesquivel.com/categories/database/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Choosing the Data Store for Your Web App</title>
      <link>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2013/choosing-the-data-store-for-your-web-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gaboesquivel.com/blog/2013/choosing-the-data-store-for-your-web-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When choosing a database for your application, you need ask yourself many questions and there are important rules about Data Architecture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there’s no standard solution that fits all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the business and it’s data defines the architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you need to find the right tool that does job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you can use multiple databases, different types depending on the characteristics of each data subset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is very important to decide carefully, after your application grown it could be very difficult to change. The CAP theorem, also known as Brewer’s theorem, states that it is impossible for a distributed computer system to simultaneously provide all three of the following guarantees:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consistency (all nodes see the same data at the same time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Availability (a guarantee that every request receives a response about whether it was successful or failed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partition tolerance (the system continues to operate despite arbitrary message loss or failure of part of the system)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;center-align-wrapper&#34;&gt;
&lt;img  alt=&#34;CAP Theorem - Venn Diagram&#34; src=&#34;https://gaboesquivel.com/img/2013/09/cap_venn.png&#34; width=&#34;547&#34; height=&#34;520&#34; /&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;
Once you have defined which of those guarantees is less important for your app and can be sacrificed, you have a smaller subset of options to choose from. However this not the only thing you need to consider, you may want to use a specific framework such as Hibernate, Spring, Django or WordPress, and take advantage of the of-the-shelf capabilities, in that case you want to use a SQL database.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
