<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Costa Rica on Gabo Esquivel - Software Engineer and Consultant</title>
    <link>/tags/costa-rica/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Costa Rica on Gabo Esquivel - Software Engineer and Consultant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/tags/costa-rica/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Software in Paradise, aka Costa Rica</title>
      <link>/blog/2014/developing-software-in-paradise-aka-costa-rica/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014/developing-software-in-paradise-aka-costa-rica/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coming back to Costa Rica and enjoy my country while working on software applications is one of the best decisions I ever made. Check out these pictures I took with my phone at Playa Manzanillo, near to Santa Teresa - Mal País, a natural paradise with world class surfing that ranks among the most beautiful beaches of Costa Rica and you&amp;rsquo;ll agree is the best place to live or invest in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;center-align-wrapper&#34;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&#34;playa-manazanillo-sunset&#34; src=&#34;/img/2014/01/playa-manazanillo-sunset-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&#34;vacas-playa-manzanillo&#34; src=&#34;/img/2014/01/vacas-playa-manzanillo-300x225.jpg&#34;/&gt;
&lt;img alt=&#34;playa-manzanillo-reef&#34; src=&#34;/img/2014/01/playa-manzanillo-reef-300x225.jpg&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&#34;rocks-playa-manzanillo&#34; src=&#34;/img/2014/01/rocks-playa-manzanillo-300x225.jpg&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Santa Teresa was recently awarded by Trip Advisor as the #1 highest-rated travel location in all of both Central and South America. Malpais and Montezuma both have many of the best restaurants in the entire country, since many international chefs have moved to the area. The area is also a major center of Costa Rica Yoga with over a dozen places to learn/practice and many yoga retreats and surf+yoga retreat combinations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://angel.co/elion-chin&#34;&gt;Elion Chin&lt;/a&gt;, co-founder of MoodLogic - one of the first online music recommendation systems, is leading &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/SiliconBeachCR&#34;&gt;Silicon Beach&lt;/a&gt; a forum for entrepreneurs &amp;amp; people looking to invest in, work at, advise or network with startups in Costa Rica to promote the technology talent of Costa Rica and drive the start-up culture in a fulfilling and healthy environment to deliver the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;center-align-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&#34;Silicon Beach Costa Rica&#34; src=&#34;/img/2014/01/silicon-beach-costa-rica.png&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&amp;nbsp;
&lt;h3&gt;Costa Rica Elevated by lostnfree&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;center-align-wrapper&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/196952762&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/196952762&#34;&gt;Costa Rica Elevated&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/nefty&#34;&gt;&amp;Nu;eftali&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Costa Rica: A Little Piece of Paradise by NatGeo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;center-align-wrapper&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/M0AqiF_pmxc&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to contact me if you are looking for advise or network with the local software development community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization in Costa Rica</title>
      <link>/blog/2013/data-visualization-in-costa-rica/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2013/data-visualization-in-costa-rica/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m very excited to announce that we&amp;#8217;re starting a data visualization meetup group in Costa Rica!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Hack/Hackers San José event I finally had the pleasure to meet &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.behance.net/Engelhardt&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Yuri Engelhardt&lt;/a&gt; in person after months of exchanging emails and ideas about data visualization. Yuri is the co-founder of &lt;a href=&#34;http://showmethedata.nl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Show Me Data&lt;/a&gt;, an annual multidisciplinary course and public event that brings together the University of Amsterdam (UvA) and the Utrecht Graduate School of Visual Art and Design (maHKU) students to get familiar with the world of data visualization. After the event we exchanged a couple more emails on the topic and we decided to create a meetup group to bring together all professionals and data visualization enthusiasts to share our knowledge and ideas. That&amp;#8217;s how the &lt;a title=&#34;Data Visualization in Costa Rica&#34; href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Data-Visualization-Costa-Rica/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Costa Rica Data Visualization Group&lt;/a&gt; was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data Visualization Costa Rica is a non-profit professional group that aims to meet monthly to discuss data visualization, data communication, infographics, exploratory data analysis, charts and graphs, perceptual psychology, and more! It is gathering point for data journalists, programmers, data scientists, business intelligence professionals, and others who tell stories with data. Meetup topics will vary and range from tutorials on basic concepts and their applications, to success stories from local practitioners, to discussions of tools, new technologies, and best practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe in data visualization, information design and digital media for social and environmental causes – e.g. in education, health, civil rights, sustainability citizen engagement, transparency and accountability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested go to &lt;a title=&#34;Data Visualization in Costa Rica&#34; href=&#34; http://meetup.com/Data-Visualization-Costa-Rica/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://meetup.com/Data-Visualization-Costa-Rica&#34;&gt;http://meetup.com/Data-Visualization-Costa-Rica&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and join us to receive notifications and updates of our events.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>